Welcome to our training on how to reduce your referral fees in select product categories.
In this video, we'll share how setting a low price for products in certain categories
can help decrease your referral fees and increase your net profits from each sale.
Referral fees for beauty, baby, health, and personal care products are 15%.
But when you set the total price of any items in these categories below $10,
you'll only pay an 8% referral fee.
Note that baby products exclude baby apparel but personal care products include personal care
appliances.
Grocery and gourmet products with a total price at or below $15 are also eligible
for 8% referral fees instead of 15%.
This isn't a discount or promotion but rather a lower referral
fee rate for lower priced products in these categories.
The lower referral fees for these
categories are available in the US, Canada, Mexico, the UK, Germany, France, Italy, and Spain.
Amazon applies the reduced referral fees to your sales automatically when the total
sales of an item are at or below the price threshold.
This is true for both fulfillment
by Amazon or FBA orders and ones you fulfill yourself.
Total prices refer to the total amount
paid by the customer which includes the item price and any shipping or gift wrapping charges
and excludes applicable taxes.
Items that meet the price threshold due to discounts like deals,
coupons, or promotions are also eligible for reduced referral fees.
Here's an example of how reduced referral fees work.
You have a grocery item priced at $15.01
meaning you pay a referral fee of $2.25 every time you sell the item.
But if you charged customers $15 for the product instead, you'd only pay a referral
fee of $1.20 for each sale.
In other words, you'd receive 7% of the revenue from that sale
to reinvest in your business.
If the current total price of your grocery and gourmet products is
between $15.01 and $16.23 in the US, a price adjustment to $15 will increase your net profits
per sale.
Here's another example.
Let's say you have a baby, beauty, or health and personal care
product priced at $10.30 meaning you pay a referral fee of $1.55 every time you sell the item.
But if you charged customers $10 for the item instead,
you'd only pay a referral fee of $0.80 for each sale and increase your net profits per sale by
$
0.44.
If the current price of your product in baby, beauty, or health and personal care product
categories is between $10.01 and $10.82 in the US, a price adjustment to $10 will result in
higher net profits per sale.
To reference a full list of referral fee percentages by category
and total price threshold, search for the referral fees help page in Seller Central and review the
referral fee rate section.
Note that prior approval may be required to offer products in certain categories.
To check your referral fee savings, select the menu icon in the top left corner of Seller Central.
Hover over inventory and select manage inventory.
If your products are priced at or below the
price thresholds that make your products eligible for a lower referral fee, review these savings
in the estimated fee per unit sold column.
For example, if your beauty or health and personal
care product is priced at $9.99, you'll see the reduced referral fee when you click the fee preview.
As a reminder, you'll automatically receive the savings from lower referral fees for all eligible
products and prices.
You can also download the referral fee preview report to view referral fees
for all items in your catalog.
To get there, open the main menu, hover over inventory,
and select inventory reports.
When you arrive at the inventory reports page,
select referral fee preview report from the select report type drop-down menu and click
request report.
This concludes our training on how to reduce your referral fees in select product
categories.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.